<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Aloma Huang</title>
    <link href="https://alomahuang.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://alomahuang.com" />
    <updated>2025-02-11T14:25:26+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>alomahunag</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://alomahuang.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Unity of Thought and Action (Or, Trying to Actually Do Things)</title>
        <author>
            <name>alomahunag</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://alomahuang.com/test.html"/>
        <id>https://alomahuang.com/test.html</id>

        <updated>2025-02-10T21:54:56+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    # Unity of Thought and Action (Or, Trying to Actually Do Things) **Solopreneur life, antique treasures, and self-improvement… all at a procrastinator’s pace.** --- This year, I’m attempting something radical: actually doing the things I think about. Novel concept, right? ## The Eternal Struggle of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    # Unity of Thought and Action (Or, Trying to Actually Do Things)  
<br>
<br>**Solopreneur life, antique treasures, and self-improvement… all at a procrastinator’s pace.**  
<br>
<br>---
<br>
<br>This year, I’m attempting something radical: actually doing the things I think about. Novel concept, right?  
<br>
<br>## The Eternal Struggle of Thinking vs. Doing  
<br>
<br>My brain? A nonstop idea factory. Business plans, creative projects, self-improvement schemes—I dream them up like it’s my job. And in those fleeting moments, I *genuinely* believe I’m about to change my life.  
<br>
<br>Reality check: I’m probably still in bed, phone in hand, scrolling, convincing myself that *thinking* about doing something is basically the same as *doing* it.  
<br>Spoiler: it’s not.  
<br>
<br>## The Lightbulb Moment  
<br>
<br>Then one day, mid-procrastination spiral, a phrase popped into my head: **unity of thought and action.**  
<br>
<br>Maybe that’s what I need—not just grand ideas, not just impulsive action, but the two working together.  
<br>
<br>## The Other Extreme: Doing Without Thinking  
<br>
<br>To be fair, I don’t *only* overthink—I also occasionally dive headfirst into action without much strategy. The result?  
<br>
<br>- Wasted energy on things that don’t matter  
<br>- A to-do list full of half-finished projects  
<br>- The realization that enthusiasm alone doesn’t equal progress  
<br>
<br>So for me, real **unity of thought and action** isn’t about acting on every whim—it’s about thinking clearly *before* acting, then actually following through.   
<br>
<br>## This Blog as My (Hopefully) Helpful Nudge  
<br>
<br>Since my brain likes to trick me into feeling productive when I’m just thinking, I need something to keep me honest. Writing it all down feels like a small step, but maybe small steps are enough to start.  
<br>
<br>By putting my thoughts out here, I hope to:  
<br>
<br>1. Turn vague ideas into something real  
<br>2. Share them with *actual people* (not just the inside of my head)  
<br>3. Create a little accountability—because if I say it out loud, I *should* probably try to do it  
<br>
<br>## Keep Me Accountable, Okay?  
<br>
<br>So, if you’re reading this—congrats, you’re now part of my anti-procrastination support group. No pressure, but feel free to call me out if I start overthinking again.  
<br>
<br>Let’s see if I can turn all these thoughts into something real. 🚀&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
